♪The white sail came too late♪
♪Where did he go?♪
♪Snow veils the mountains♪
♪Love endures beyond life and death♪
♪A black chess piece♪
♪Whose game did he stumble into?♪
♪All his life, there's no escape♪
♪In ten thousand years, what will still remain?♪
♪Will anyone still love with an unchanging heart?♪
♪I will remember♪
♪Those days long past♪
♪As the wind drifts with the white sail♪
♪Ten thousand years ago♪
♪Did you once walk this shore?♪
♪Why can't our bond be severed in this life?♪
♪I am lost yet willing♪
♪Still I love you with a steadfast heart♪
♪Until all things fade away♪
♪The stars will remember us♪
[Love & Crown]
[Adapted from the novel "My Queen" by Xie Lounan]
[Episode 6]
Enjoy, Your Majesty.
So
what did you put
in the liquor?
You know I spiked the drink,
but you drank it still.
I thought
you had put some potent venom.
So it was just to trigger my cold sickness.
I just need you to stay here for one more night.
I need the Phoenix Seal.
Otherwise, I can't do much in the palace.
My dear, you're
too naive.
You think keeping me here
will get you the Phoenix Seal from the Empress Dowager?
Father aided you for many years.
Empress Dowager Liu is our common enemy.
You want your power.
I have my goal.
We can work together.
Even willing to look past
what happened before?
Yes.
Xiaoyue, you're back.
I don't want to talk about it.
- Madam. - Madam.
What happened to His Majesty?
Her Majesty seems to have offended His Majesty.
Ling Cangcang.
Where is your respect?
Who said you could come in?
Get lost!
Yes, Your Majesty.
I am unable to ascertain
what happened in the chamber.
But His Majesty was lashing out against Her Majesty.
He even hollered at Imperial Preceptor Du who barged in thereafter.
It seems like Her Majesty hasn't earned
His Majesty's favor.
Indeed.
It means nothing even if she's the daughter of Ling Xuefeng.
She's just a stepping stone
for Xiao Huan to amass more power.
Then shall we proceed with the plans
we have devised against her?
No need.
A disfavored Empress is no threat.
Xiao Huan doesn't love her.
So she isn't my enemy.
In that case,
I'm sure
she'll be too ashamed to get the Phoenix Seal from you.
By His Majesty's decree,
Her Majesty's oversight has caused
the resurgence of His Majesty's cold sickness.
As an act of punishment,
His Majesty declares
that from now on,
Her Majesty cannot leave the inner palace.
May Her Majesty profit
from this period to reflect upon herself.
Father.
I have bad news.
What is it?
Why the panic?
Her Majesty
has been grounded.
Grand Tutor Ling, did you rush into the palace
for whatever reason?
I must have spoiled my daughter
that she grew flippant.
That's why you had to put her in place.
I came to apologize
on her behalf.
It's not that serious, Grand Tutor Ling.
The Empress poisoned my drink
in an attempt to harm me.
But I knew that if
I punished the Empress in accordance with the law,
ministers in the court
would think that there was discord
between us.
So I made a declaration
that the Empress had angered me
and was grounded as a result.
Are you happy
with such an approach?
Thank you for your mercy, Your Majesty.
You're welcome.
Alas, I am still plagued by my sickness.
I count on you to handle
the endless matters in the court.
I wish to consult
your opinion on one matter.
Do tell.
The talent recommendation system
will bring a boon to our nation.
After several days of research
and deliberations,
I've decided
to agree with the suggestion of the Ministry of Personnel.
We should implement the system.
I am glad to see your devotion
to our national welfare, Grand Tutor Ling.
[Ling Manor]
Father.
You're back.
Fortunately, this drawing
can yet be saved.
Otherwise, I'll have to discard and redraw it.
Father,
what did your visit
to the palace yield?
What did it yield?
His Majesty grounded Cangcang
so that I'd agree to let
Song Lanxi assume office in the Capital.
He used Cangcang again.
For my daughter,
I'm willing to concede.
But Father...
Don't worry.
If I can raise a dragon,
I can tame it.
Once Cangcang is conceived with a child,
a young emperor who died before the age of 30
won't be a threat.
His Majesty implements the talent recommendation system
in order to shuffle the current power dynamics in court.
That will not do me or Liu
any good.
Even if I concede,
I'm sure
Liu
will do something about it.
His Majesty allows Qing to return to the Capital?
Yes.
Because Qing has to escort
that Song back?
Song Lanxi.
I knew he was up to no good.
I disagreed with the talent recommendation system.
So he wants to use Qing to deal with me.
Calm down, Your Majesty.
His Highness is coming back.
You will be freed from the pain
of missing your son.
If Qing escorted Song Lanxi to the Capital safely,
Xiao Huan would be able to implement the new policy.
It would not do us any good.
If they had an accident, however,
Qing would bear full liability.
Xiao Huan
is getting smarter and smarter.
What should we do then?
Qing is at stake.
I cannot act recklessly.
We'll let them return to the Capital safely.
Fortunately for us, Song Lanxi
is only slightly popular among the nobles.
He is young and inexperienced.
Using him to implement the new policy
will not be as easy.
It's late now.
Her Majesty must be asleep now.
Xiaoyue who serves the Empress works for the Dowager Empress.
Find a way to get rid of her.
I don't want any unscrupulous party
to be working closely with her.
It'll be done, Your Majesty.
Wufu.
The Empress's palace could use some decorations.
Find some art pieces
and give them to her tomorrow.
And tell her
that the confinement has been lifted.
Noted, Your Majesty.
I'm sure
Her Majesty will appreciate Your Majesty's gesture
once she received the drawings.
Cangcang,
I used you again.
You must
resent me even more now.
Here. Roll it.
Okay.
Your Majesty.
Have you arranged for the candidates
to enter the Capital?
Rest assured, Your Majesty.
Shi Yan has brought the candidates to Chu.
Fenglai Pavilion will assist further
and Prince of Yuzhang will escort them.
Additionally,
Lingbi Sect is now left leaderless,
and has suffered great loss.
Their disciples are vying for power now.
Ling Xuefeng will not be able to do much for now.
The Lingbi Sect might have fallen apart,
but it's not gone yet.
Even though Ling Xuefeng has lost his forces in the martial world,
he still has murder thralls.
We cannot underestimate him.
Right.
But Your Majesty,
you are wary of the Grand Tutor.
Why did you summon Prince of Yuzhang back here?
Because I can profit
from some infighting.
Your Majesty.
Eunuch Feng is here.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
You're here, Eunuch Feng.
His Majesty asked me
to bring some drawings as gifts for you.
Here.
Allow me to thank His Majesty.
Is he recovering from his cold sickness?
Worry not, Your Majesty.
His Majesty is doing well.
He is now discussing
important matters in Wuying Hall with Grand Tutor Ling.
His Majesty sure is shrewd.
Your Majesty,
His Majesty misses you a lot.
Look.
He also asked me to come here to tell you
that your confinement had been lifted.
The drawings...
I understand, Eunuch Feng.
You may return.
Okay.
By your leave.
Your Majesty.
Do you want to look at His Majesty's gifts?
No.
Put them aside.
[Southern Chu]
[Fenglai Pavilion]
[List of Candidates]
[Zhang Yu, Lin Chuwei]
I only have to escort a few people back to the Capital.
Why must I enlist Fenglai Pavilion's help too?
The martial world is dangerous,
and our enemies hide in the shadows.
We must be careful.
Besides,
it's a precondition for your return to the Capital.
Fine.
I cannot defy His Majesty's decree.
If Fenglai Pavilion is assisting me,
how many of you will be there?
Zhong Lin, Vice Sect Leader
of Fenglai Pavilion,
will be at your service.
I'll escort you back to the Capital.
Miss Zhong,
this is not right.
You have been managing
Fenglai Pavilion, Mr. Shi.
I'm free
and could use some exercise.
What's wrong with that?
You
must be Miss Zhong.
I haven't settled the score of that hideous tattoo.
And here you are, surrendering yourself.
Your Highness.
You want a peacock tattoo.
That's easy.
Once you bring me to the Capital,
I'll modify your tattoo into a peacock.
Bring you to the Capital?
Do you
want to see Ling Cangcang?
Sorry.
I was born selfish.
Altruism is not
in my nature.
What a shame.
Shi Yan.
There's only one such name list.
Is that right?
Miss Zhong.
What are you doing?
I don't have many talents,
but I have a good memory.
The name, age, physical descriptions,
and habits
of the candidates on the name list
are all seared in my mind.
However,
if Your Highness insists on not bringing me back to the Capital,
I'll miss Cangcang so much
and fall into depression.
When
that happens, I might just
forget everything.
The powder you used just now...
It's phosphor.
And the different pouches you're carrying...
They contain different powders
with different effects.
Wow.
Miss Zhong,
you are brave and smart.
You will come with us.
But no.
Your Highness,
His Majesty asked me to come with you.
The entire Fenglai Pavilion can come
with me.
Your Highness,
why did His Majesty
summon you back to the Capital?
[Fenglai Pavilion]
Who knows what happened in his crazy mind?
But knowing him,
it's not a good thing.
But I haven't returned in many years.
I do miss Mother and Ying.
We'll cross the bridge when we get there.
Zhong Lin is witty and cunning.
Why did you pick her, Your Highness?
Are you dumb?
Shi Yan works for His Majesty.
Right.
Putting you on escort duty must be a trap.
If Shi Yan pulls a trick during the journey
and the candidates are in danger,
you'll be implicated.
Zhong Li doesn't get along with Shi Yan well.
Wise choice, Your Highness.
Ask everyone in the manor to get ready.
I want to return to the Capital already.
Are you not taking me, Your Highness?
For you to mess everything up?
Stay here
to watch Shi Yan closely.
Your Majesty, for once, you're in a good mood.
Did something good happen?
A friend outside of the palace wrote to me,
saying that she'd be in the Capital soon.
Speaking of which,
we haven't met for a while.
I miss her.
How wonderful.
I'm happy for you, Your Majesty.
The Begonia Pendant lit up.
[Pristine Integrity]
What is this place?
Your Majesty,
this is the cold palace where Princess Ying resides.
A cold palace?
How come I've never heard of this place?
And who is Princess Ying?
It's only normal that you did not know, Your Majesty.
Princess Ying is a taboo subject in the palace.
No one brings her up.
Tell me more.
Tell me.
We are alone here.
Well,
Princess Ying is the Empress Dowager's adoptive daughter.
Her birth mother passed away early.
Prince of Yuzhang brought her back to Xuanguang Hall.
When she was little, she was close to His Majesty.
But then, there was an inferno all of a sudden
and she almost lost her life there.
Princess Ying suffered a great shock.
She became addled upon being rescued.
They had no choice
but to put her here.
An inferno all of a sudden?
Why would the Empress Dowager let her only daughter
stay in such a forsaken place?
Actually,
that is Princess Ying's own decision.
After she survived the inferno,
she became afraid of her own palace.
But wherever she relocated to,
she would run out in distress.
She only manages to calm herself down
in the cold palace.
The Empress Dowager had no other choice.
Let's go.
The Begonia Pendant never lights up,
but it reacts to the cold palace.
How odd.
Do not touch my belongings!
[Xiao Ying, Princess of Great Qi]
I do not like you.
Go away.
You don't know me.
Why do you not like me?
I know who you are.
His Majesty got married the other day.
No one invited me,
but I snuck out to watch the ceremony.
I hate you.
I hate anyone who has ties with Xiao Huan.
Then you should like me.
Because
I hate Xiao Huan too.
Why did you marry him then?
I had no choice.
You are able-bodied.
What do you mean you had no choice?
I came
to ask you something.
Maybe
you could help me.
Do you recognize this Begonia Pendant?
If you kill Xiao Huan for me,
I'll tell you everything.
What?
You don't want him killed?
Then you don't hate him for real.
Go away.
I want him killed.
But he is the Emperor.
No one can kill him easily.
I can.
What?
Are you scared now?
If you are scared, you can still run.
Otherwise,
I might kill you too.
You only chase me out because you can't
answer my question.
You don't know what it is at all.
And you don't know
why it lit up.
I do!
Then tell me.
Azure firefly.
You know many things.
Yes.
This is an azure firefly as recorded in the Tome of All Venom
It grew up ingesting the poisonous powder I made.
It is afraid of my pendant.
Amazing.
It scares my firefly.
Your pendant
must have contained Wanwei Herb,
a precious herb
that will light up to expel all venomous creatures near it.
With it,
no venomous bugs can hurt you.
Why would Master give me a special artifact
as an ordinary accessory?
Where did you
get this amazing artifact?
My master gave it to me.
Your master is so sweet.
He was very kind to me.
But
he was killed.
By Xiao Huan?
That's why you hate him.
Yes.
I have
a limitless supply of poisons.
I can help you kill him.
Your Majesty,
Her Majesty went to the cold palace.
Cold palace?
What for?
Princess Ying said
she wanted to help her kill you.
Your Majesty,
allow me to bring her back.
No need.
Your Majesty,
I am worried about Her Majesty.
Princess Ying might hurt her.
She won't.
They have a common enemy.
Xiao Ying wants to use her to kill me.
She won't hurt her.
Worry not, Your Majesty.
Her Majesty did not agree to her request.
[Linghe Hall]
Stop drinking, Your Majesty.
It's bad for your health.
No,
it's bad if I don't drink it.
You're drunk, Your Majesty.
You should stop drinking.
Drunk?
I'm not drunk.
You don't believe me?
Come.
Let's have an arm wrestle.
Zhong Lin and I played it a lot.
And she never won.
Come.
Your Majesty, you're teasing me again.
You're a heroine.
I can't win even if you're drunk.
Heroine?
I'm not a heroine.
I'm just
a caged canary bird.
Drink up!
Be careful, Your Majesty.
You soaked the drawings.
Your Majesty, I didn't expect to see this side of you.
You're so cool
and free-spirited.
I'm sure the author of this drawing
must be very close to you.
Why do you say so?
Because Your Majesty smiles so brightly in the drawing.
I've never
seen you like this.
His Majesty has arrived.
Why did you come here?
To apologize.
Apologize?
I spiked your drink.
You committed no fault.
If that's the case,
would you want to drink with me?
What if I poisoned you again?
It doesn't matter.
Come.
Drink up.
Do you remember
the first time we climbed to the roof?
The audacity of you to bring it up.
I bet
I've always been the bargaining chip
for you to fight against my father.
Tell me now.
What is your agenda this time?
Whatever justification
I bring up will be useless.
Exactly.
I don't believe
in any word you say.
What about the Phoenix Seal?
Do you still want it?
What?
Are you helping me?
Or lying to me?
Lying to me again.
Come.
Drink up.
Look.
Our relationship
is just
like this cup.
It's broken.
No.
Our relationship
is just a pipe dream of mine.
Cangcang.
You're drunk.
No, I'm not.
I just
don't get it.
Why did you kill my master?
I don't get it.
Did you approach me
just to kill my master?
Cangcang.
I'm serious about you.
And your serious commitment
can kill.
♪Why can't our bond be severed in this life...♪
Drink up!
♪Until all things fade away♪
Are you happy?
Let's find our new ally.
No wonder you won't kill Xiao Huan.
He
likes you.
Come in, mister.
I'm coming!
Come inside.
How may I help, sir?
It's summer now.
You must have fresh pufferfish.
We are a group of 30-something travelers.
One braised pufferfish with rushes for everyone, please.
Sir,
we do have pufferfish.
But unfortunately, we don't have a chef
who can cook pufferfish here.
Gold?
You shall have fresh pufferfish tonight!
You will be served our best Sangluo Wine
as well.
Come.
Follow me.
Let's go.
Xiao Qianqing made a huge deal out of his escort duty
with regards to the candidates.
Everyone knows about it.
I found
this new blade for you.
It's light and gentle.
You have trouble using a blade due to your missing right index finger.
This blade
will suit you well.
Thank you, Father.
Xiao Qianqing.
They call him
the Peacock Prince.
He isn't as superficial
as he seems.
He's returning to the Capital in grandeur
because he wants to meddle in the implementation of the new system.
We cannot give him the opportunity to do this.
You must
eliminate Song Lanxi and the rest.
Kill everyone you think
is your target.
I know you are rich,
but it's better to lie low
when you're escorting someone to the Capital.
A humble peacock
is no different from a fowl.
If someone has ill intentions,
being discreet will not make a difference.
You're so gullible.
An unfallen mulberry leaf
is endowed with plump leaves.
A fallen mulberry leaf
is crisp and mellow.
The Sangluo Wine mustn't be savored like this.
Servants!
Sir.
Bring my ice here.
Sure.
You are a heroine, yes.
But rolling your eyes
is an indecent thing to do.
I will attend to other officials.
Enjoy your meal.
I have a question.
Song Lanxi is just a new,
lowly candidate.
Why must we kill him?
Who Song Lanxi is doesn't matter.
What matters
is his tutor, Li Chengtian.
He was my rival in the court for many years,
and gave me many headaches.
While he retired many years ago,
his influence runs deep
and can still be felt.
The moral ones in the court view him as a leader.
I understand now.
If Xiao Huan uses Song Lanxi to entice
Li Chengtian into coming back,
that will be a threat to us.
Song Lanxi
is Li Chengtian's student after he went into retirement.
Not many know that.
Even I only found out recently.
Again, His Majesty
is one step ahead of me.
It's my fault.
We have lost our head start.
You cannot make any mistakes now.
And make sure to leave no traces behind
that reveal who you are.
Yes, Father.
I will not let you down.
Your Majesty,
please put it on.
It's okay. I'm not cold.
Your Majesty,
it's late and misty now.
Even if you're not cold,
you must make sure you won't catch a cold.
I'm fine.
This is...
Someone wants to see me.
They worked together flawlessly
and killed them in one slash.
They left none alive.
What a professional group of assassins.
It's good that you found criminals on the death row
to impersonate them.
Do you understand why I maintain a high profile now?
Yes.
It's just a small trick.
What small trick?
I am brave and wise.
My tactics are unrivaled.
We still have
to exercise caution.
The Capital is far.
We might run into another incident.
I must live till I get to the Capital
and find Cangcang.
Don't worry.
You can count on me.
Bad news!
Your Highness.
Official Song...
What happened?
For some reason, Official Song
left on his own.
When I found him,
he was barely alive.
He will die soon.
We did everything we could,
but it was still not enough.
What do we do now?
Official Song is a priority.
If something happens to him,
Xiao Huan will say
that I failed in my duty to escort him.
I cannot let this happen.
Let me think of a solution.
♪Dust gathers on the lost paths of time♪
♪A red candle keeps the dusk company in solitude♪
♪Blurred words on faded bamboo slips♪
♪Broken speech in twisted time♪
♪The heart still hums its old song of longing♪
♪On Phoenix Terrace, the seasons weave their tales in turn♪
♪Tears fall, nourishing all living things♪
♪Be it cloud or rain, sea or flower♪
♪The annual rings carve deep and shallow scars♪
♪In the end, silence is the only reply♪
♪Oh, broken-hearted one, still you wander the world♪
♪The setting sun listens to the tide's confession♪
♪A beam of moonlight keeps the hesitant poet company♪
♪Amid the swirling mortal dust, love and hate are hopelessly entwined♪
♪Empty cups greet the dawn of parting♪
♪The heart still hums its old song of longing♪
♪On Phoenix Terrace, the seasons weave their tales in turn♪
♪That iridescent soul gleams through the drifting past♪
♪Be it cloud or rain, sea or flower♪
♪The annual rings carve deep and shallow scars♪
♪When will the old friend answer?♪
♪Oh, wandering soul, one day you'll find your way home♪